Princetoniana Committee Oral History Project Records, 1994-2015: Preliminary Finding Aid AC259
University Archives
- Series 2: Princetoniana Committee Oral History Interviews, 1977-2015 May 12; 3 boxes
  - William Selden '34, 2006; 1 box (Box 4)
    In his interview, Selden talks about Princeton's lack of general selectivity but presence of targeted selectivity in admitting Jewish students; religious life on campus; the admittance of Roman Catholics in the 1890s; the creation of the Woodrow Wilson school as the first cross-departmental opportunity; Wilson's general dislike of the University; Jewish presence in eating clubs; Asians as a minority on campus; lack of political activity on campus; serving as the Princetonian's business manager; selling Princeton town merchants scrip for Daily Prince ads; the Depression on campus; serving as chairman of the Tiger Prince Prom; House parties and supervising chaperones; the University's class attendance policy; lack of diversity; the precept system; public high school kids not being admitted; half of freshmen living off campus; being a member of Cap and Gown Club; involvement with Stock and Bus in Theater Intime; mentions Deans Gauss and Eisenhart; Presidents Dodds and Goheen; Admissions Director Radcliffe Hermance; and Professor Corwin.
  - Jay Sherrerd '52 and Anne Sherrerd *87, 2007; 1 box (Box 4)
    Jay Sherrerd, Class of 1952, majored in Economics. He has served as a Charter Club trustee, Chairman of the Board of Trustees, and chair of the Princeton investment committee.
    Anne Sherrerd, Graduate Class of 1987, accompanied her father during his interview. Jay Sherrerd discusses interacting with football player Bob Peters; rooming with 4 classmates from the Hill School at Princeton; the divisiveness of the coeducation debate; playing freshman basketball; Princeton athletics; the lack of segregation between athletes and non-athletes on campus; participating in ROTC; serving in the Army after college; attending the Wharton School; annual giving involvement; attending 56 reunions; extensive involvement with Princeton as an alum; having a piano in his dorm room; the constant debate about the eating club system; the '52 petition movement to get everyone to agree not to join an eating club unless everyone got bids; hic class's nickname "radical class of 1952"; classmates Eric Merrifield, Joe Bolster, Chuck DeVoe, Poss Parham, and George Sella; basketball coach Cappy Cappon; and Bill Hardt.
  - Paul Sigmund, 2012; 1 box (Box 4)
    Paul Sigmund is Emeritus Professor of Politics at Princeton. He attended Georgetown University for his undergraduate education. He served as Quincy House Senior Tutor worked at Harvard, where he received his Ph.D. and worked from 1951 to 1963 before coming to Princeton. At Princeton, he served as Director of the Latin American Studies Department.
    Sigmund shares that he was born in Berlin but grew up in Philadelphia; won the Quiz Kids show competition; attended Georgetown University; served as Regional Head of the International Relations Club Association; attended St. Joseph's Prep School; spent a year at the University of Durham on a Fulbright Scholarship; worked at Harvard from 1951 to 1963; came to Princeton in the February 1963; taught Politics 101; taught political development, political theory, Latin American politics; and comparative politics courses; subsidized by the Rockefeller Foundation; received Ph.D. from Harvard and stayed as a lecturer; served as Senior Tutor at Harvard in Quincy House; wife is from the Claiborne family; worked as a consultant to the State Department; taught Politics 210; and worked as Director of the Latin American Studies Department.
  - John B. (Jack) Smiley '49, 2011; 1 box (Box 4)
    John Smiley, Class of 1949, served as his class's president for 2 years. He attended Princeton Theological Seminary after college, eventually becoming a minister.
    In his interview, Smiley talks about attending Shady Side Academy; visiting his brother at Princeton and attending precepts with him; WWII on campus; living in Little Hall; academic intensity; married classmates; the Cane Spree; going to New York on VJ-Day; writing his thesis on Quaker religious beliefs; Walter "Buzzer" Hall's nickname; Professor Erdman Harris "Jinks" Harbison; preceptor Carlos Baker; President Dodds; playing baseball and basketball and JV football for 1 year; serving on the Undergraduate Council; writing sports for The Daily Prince; attending the First Presbyterian Church; basketball coaches Cappy Cappon and eddie Donovan; not being allowed to have girls over to dorms; import girls; being a member of Tiger Inn; political makeup of the class; Professor Philip Crowl; President Goheen as a preceptor; attending Princeton Theological Seminary; working as a minister; and beating the University of Pennsylvania in football in 1946.
  - Kathy Taylor '74, 2009; 1 box (Box 4)
    Kathy Taylor, Class of 1974, majored in English. She served as treasurer for the Princeton Club of Philadelphia and the first female Director of the Alumni Council.
    Taylor discusses growing up in Hollidaysburg, Pennsylvania; her Princeton family, her grandfather '39, father, and brothers Jim '67 and David '69 had all attended; her brother David dropping out of Princeton; her father's death occurring right before coming to Princeton; the small amount of girls on campus; serving as Chair of the Board at Baldwin; her father being a progressive proponent of Planned Parenthood and creating a family planning center at the hospital he worked for; resenting having to be on financial aid; working at the Student Agencies Office; rude comments from male classmates about females on campus; taking Roman Law with Professor Bourne who resented coeducation; Professor Larry Danson; attending the University of Pennsylvania for graduate school, but leaving to work for Girard Bank; singing for the Tigerlilies and being Music Director; being a member of Triangle Club; The Grotto Restaurant; classmate Jeff Wieser; the Princeton Club of Philadelphia; teaching at her high school alma mater, Baldwin; Baldwin's making her a strong woman; and the Princeton alumni community.
  - Deborah A. Tegarden '71, 2015 February 17; 1 box (Box 4)
    Deborah Tegarden, Class of 1971.
    Tegarden attended Princeton High School before attending Princeton University, however, she transferred from Brown, because Princeton had not gone co-ed yet. In the transcripts, Tegarden talks about the "co-eds" living together at Pyne Hall; women being called "Sue Pynes"; joining Wilson College and then Colonial Club; marrying a member of the class of 1966; majoring in Religion; being one of the first female members of Colonial Club; working at the University Press; Wilson College being an "experimental college" in the beginning; the Cambodia Strike in the Chapel; getting involved politically on campus; camping out overnight outside the Dow Chemical research center for political strikes; males on campus being supportive of the movement to co-education; one student barricading himself in the Colonial women's room to protest co-education; being involved in Chapel Choir, Glee Club, and theater InTime; having great relationships with professors; finding religion at Princeton; her father as a Unitarian minister; not having many female friends on campus; drugs on campus; casino night events at Colonial Club; house parties on campus; and reunions. She mentions Professor Emeritus John Fleming and Glee Club Director Walter Nollner.
  - Eleanor Anne (Ellie) Vivona-Vaughan '79, 1977-2014 June 21; 1 box
    Eleanor Anne (Ellie) Vivona-Vaughan, class of 1979, transferred to Princeton in 1977, as one of the few older "Continuing Ed" females on campus.
    - Eleanor Anne (Ellie) Vivona-Vaughan '79 Transcript, 2014 June 21; 1 box (Box 4)
      Vivona-Vaughan attended Union Community College before transferring to Princeton in 1977. She discusses growing up poor in the Bronx; attending Berkeley Business School in New York; married her husband in 1969; working as a secretary at Mobil Oil Company; having children shortly after marriage; the difficulty in navigating Catholic traditions and being an independent woman; being Valedictorian and elected to Phi Theta Kappa at Union Community College; accompanying a friend, Lisa Hyder, to her admissions tour at Princeton; being invited to sit in Lisa Hyder's, interview by Jane Sharaf, the Director of Transfer Admissions; Jane Sharaf lobbying for her admission, even though she was not popular with the "old boy's network;" being the subject of The Westfield Suburban News article "Graduating Mom Combines Home, School Successfully;" living in a run-down handyman's special in Princeton Junction to make ends meet; experiencing culture shock at Princeton and the lack of no "true religion," being around younger students; feeling welcomed to campus; being encouraged by preceptor Ed Holmes; the difficulty of Princeton academics; bringing her sons to meetings with Deans; never attending reunions; the difficulty of being an older transfer student; associating mostly with Continuing Ed classmates; being awarded the Frank Junior McConnell Memorial Scholarship; and juggling having children with attending classes. She mentions Elaine Gross, an older classmate; Dean Cucchi; classmate and Vietnam veteran David Grady; and Professor Julian Jaynes.
    - Eleanor Anne (Ellie) Vivona-Vaughan '79 Supplementary Materials, 1977-1979; 1 box (Box 4)
      Includes documents related to scholarships and newspaper articles.
  - Laurie Seligman Wallmark '76, 2014; 1 box (Box 4)
    Laurie Seligman Wallmark was Class of 1976.
    Seligman talks about attending a pre-Princeton admissions meeting at the Westfield Tennis Club, which was normally was closed to Jews; participating in civil rights rallies; being the only woman in some classes; having to search for other women on campus; subconscious campus segregation; the academic rigor; Princeton Inn College being an enclave of women; having a gay friend who never came out at Princeton; dating a graduate student; meeting her husband during sophomore year; the dating scene; the Princeton name helping with employment; lack of public school kids at Princeton; being a member of Campus Club; residential colleges; eating at Commons; Terrace being the alternative club; worked as a software engineer and as a consultant after college
  - Malcolm Warnock '25, 2005; 1 box (Box 4)
    Malcolm Warnock, Class of 1925, majored in History.
    Warnock, in his interview, discusses living in Edwards; football player classmate Snively; organ recitals in the graduate college on Sundays; being rejected fro the Glee Club; playing in and traveling with the orchestra; playing on the club hockey tea; waiting on the tables in the Commons; being a member of Key and Seal Club; the bicker process; the ROTC having horses students could ride; receiving a scholarship to come to Princeton; and being admitted to Princeton without taking any exams.
  - Marina von Neumann Whitman, 2013; 1 box (Box 4)
    Marina Whitman, trustee of the University from 1980-1990 meanwhile an overseer of Harvard.
    Whitman talks about her father as a Rockerfeller Fellow with Eugene Wigner in 1930 and his move to the Institute of Advanced Study in 1933; her parents' work at Brookhaven Laboratory; attending Radcliffe for undergrad; trying to petition to complete a Ph.D. in Economics at Princeton in 1957 but being told by President Dodds that there weren't sufficient facilities for women; receiving her Ph.D. in economics at Columbia; working as Vice President of General Motors in 1980, the highest ranking female in the auto industry; Princeton as a "benevolent monarchy…run out of Nassau Hall"; the evolution of the role of Princeton's president; and her father's work on MANIAC at the Institute for Advanced Study.
  - Hugh (Bud) Wynne '39, 2007; 1 box (Box 4)
    Hugh "Bud" Wynne, Class of 1939, and first chairman of the Princetoniana Committee.
    In the transcript, Wynne describes Vondermuhll Class of 1904, his godfather, influencing his decision to come to Princeton; participating in ROTC as the "supreme commander" for the Class of 1939; membership in the Triangle Club; traveling with the Triangle Club; friendship with and the character of Jack Kennedy, a Princeton and Choate School classmate; membership in Cottage Club; seeing Einstein on campus; friendship with Ashby Harper, a classmate; Professor Erling Dorf in geology; playing lacrosse at Princeton; Freddy Fox's knack to know what students needed; creating the Princetoniana Committee; finding the "Christian Student" statue, which was taken out of Princeton during his undergraduate years, brought back to Princeton, and put near Jadwin renamed the "Princeton Student" statue; and finding the model of the Fitz-Randolph gates, which is now in Mudd Library.
  - Wendy Zaharko '74, 2009; 1 box (Box 4)
    Wendy Zaharko, Class of 1974.
    Zaharko discusses attending Mt. Pleasant High School in Delaware; her high school activist community; meeting Jay Webster, Class of 1961 and receiving an application for Princeton in the mail marked "fill this out and send it in"; her friendship with Jay Webster; highschool and Princeton classmate and roommate Sally Fields; Sally Fields finishing school in 3 years; living in Pyne Hall, which was initially all for women; the toilet's having springs on them so they were always up for boys, and taking pliers to cut the springs; Cathy Corcione living near her, an Olympic swimmer; talking to Assistant Director of Admissions Laurence Sanford who told her she was accepted to Princeton to please male alums, because she was an athlete; the large amount of females that were also athletes at Princeton; the beginnings of the women's squash team; having to share squash courts with the men; traveling to squash games in a "Princeton University" limousine; the squash uniforms; expecting to meet a Princeton man and get married; not liking the huge amount of men compared to women; the rigor of the pre-med classes; being called "Mr." on accident by one professor; the Honor Code stating "on my honor as a gentleman"; girls coming in from other schools on the weekends; the dating scene; eating clubs being closed to women for the first two years; bickering Cap and Gown, but dropping Cap for Charter; involved in the anti-war movement called the Movement for a New Congress; charging alcohol to student account at Chancellor Green; drugs on campus including LSD; Boone's Farm Apple Wine; African-American and Asian presence on campus; classmate Michelle Obama; homosexuality on campus; Abby Rubenfeld, head of the class, and a lesbian; the differences between how men and women carried books; starting the gym shorts trend among women
- Series 3: Butler Apartments Oral History Interviews, 2013-2015; 1 box
  No arrangement action taken or arrangement information not recorded at the time of processing.
  Series 3 consists of transcripts of interviews with individuals who lived at the Butler Apartments (which is scheduled to be razed in 2014) between 1965 and 2013. The interviews were conducted in 2013, 2014 and 2015.
  - Subseries 3A, Butler Apartments Oral History Interviews from May and June 2013, 2013 May-June; 1 box (Box 5)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    AR.2013.127
    Subseries 3A consists of transcripts of interviews with 16 individuals who lived at the Butler Apartments (which will be razed in 2014) between 1965 and 2013. The interviews were conducted in May and June of 2013; the interviewees include: Kristine Bietsch, Ph.D. candidate, 2015; Joe Danks *1968 and Carol Danks; Richard Darilek *1973; Johanna Goldman, Ph.D. candidate, 2015; Laura Kahn, Ph.D. candidate, 2015; Beth Kosiak *1993; Dawn LaValle Ph.D. candidate, 2014; Bill Lehrman *1989; Ricardo Reyes Heroles Ph.D. candidate, 2015, and Francesca Arienzo; Dan Zeltzer, Ph.D. candidate, 2015, and Elsat Kadem; Daniel Sanchez *2013; and Michael Zdilla *2005 and Gail Zdilla.
    The transcripts are arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 3B, Butler Apartments Oral History Interviews from October 2013 to 2015, 2013-2015; 1 box
    Subseries 3B consists of transcripts of interviews with 30 individuals who lived at the Butler Apartments between 1951 and 2014. Topics discussed include living conditions,expenses,commuting,childcare arrangements,the international community,and the relationship with the surrounding Princeton neighborhood.
    - Michael Axelrod *66 and Joyce Axelrod, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - David Baldwin *65, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      David Baldwin is a political scientist at the Woodrow Wilson School and is a member of the Council of Foreign Relations.
      The Baldwin interview includes an anecdote about former university president, William G. Bowen
    - Adam J. Berger *95, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Topics adressed in the Berger interview include housing in the Graduate College and the international community at Butler.
    - Christine Blumauer, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Christine Blumauer is the spouse of Sebastien Philippe, Ph.D. candidate, 2017.
    - W. Michael Blumenthal *54 *56, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      W.Michael Blumenthal served as the United States Secretary of Treasury under the Carter Administration. He is also the founding Director of the Jewish Museum Berlin.
    - Christine Chalifoux, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Christine Chalifoux is the spouse of Quincy Amoah, Ph.D candidate, 2018.
    - Sam Clark *14, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Ronald Davidson *66 and Jean Davidson, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Ronald Davidson is a former director of the Princeton Plasma Physics Laboratory and is a professor emeritus in the Astrophysical Sciences department.
    - Paul Firbas *01 and Carolina Firbas, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - John H. Fleming *87, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Edward J. Groth III *71, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Edward J. Groth III has conducted extensive research on the Hubble Space Telescope while serving on the faculty of the Physics department.
    - Curtis Hillegas *02, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Curt Hillegas has served as Director of Research Computing and managed TIGRESS, the university's Terascale Infrastructure for engineering research.
    - David N. Hingston *74, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Edith Jeffrey, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Edith Jeffrey is the spouse of Richard Jeffrey *57, who taught in the Philosophy department from 1974-1999.
    - David N. Kinsey *75, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Ulrich C. Knoepflmacher *61, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
      Ulrich C. Knoepflmacher is a professor emeritus in the English Department.
    - Xiuyuan (Suzanne) Lu *97, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Robert H. Lupton *85, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Marina Mitchell *98, 2015; 1 box (Box 5)
      Marina Mitchell has served as the chair of Graduate Alumni Annual Giving and as a member of the Board of Governors of the Princeton Association of New York City
    - Michelle Nielsen, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - David C. Parris *70, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Armond T. Perretta *74, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Tobias D. Robison *65 and Elaine Golden Robison *72, 2015; 1 box (Box 5)
      The Robison interview includes details of Elaine Golden Robison's collaboration with Associate Dean Paul Benacerraf in changing aspects of Butler's housing policy.
    - Joseph V. Sullivan *82, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Howard C. Wainer *68, 2014; 1 box (Box 5)
    - Marina von Neumann Whitman, 2013; 1 box (Box 5)
      Marina von Neumann Whitman is an economist and a former university trustee. She has served as Vice President of the General Motors Corporation and on the boards of many other organizations. She is also the spouse of Robert Freeman Whitman, professor of English, and the daughter of the mathematician John von Neumann.
      Whitman discussed her experiences living at the Butler Apartments in the mid-1950s, including the austere living conditions, anecdotes about having former University President Bill Bowen and his wife as neighbors, as well as the impact of the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 on her family.